

Nice to meet you, my name is Francisco (Paco) Martínez.

I am a Mexican, Full Stack Product Designer, currently on a Design Leadership career path. I have formed and scaled successful teams of designers —on my own company and others— as well as executed outstanding projects on various branches of Design.

- 10+ years of experience executing design projects around Visual Identity, User Experience and Product Design.
- 6+ years of experience as Entrepreneur; as well as building and leading Design teams.

Waterloo, ON, Canada

- +1 226 666 7399 (CAN)
- +51 81 8015 2254 (MX)

hello@pacomartinez.design

- linkedin.com/in/franciscomartínez-4891924a
- medium.com/@paco\_mtz\_design

### **Experience**

### 2018-Present

# Design Director Insticator

Company Type: Technology Startup
Dates Employed: November 2018 – Present
Employment Duration: 1 yr 6 mos
Location: Waterloo, ON, Canada

- Directed and / or executed key research and product design projects (customer-facing and internal tools)
- Implemented a Design Operations practice in the form of updated tools and cross-functional collaboration processes (e.g. design sprints)
- Promoted user research practices to help derisk product initiatives
- Updated all of the brand's touchpoints through a lean brand redesign
- Kickstarted an internal marketing function focused on content creation and brand validation

# 2017—2018

# Head of Design Icalia Labs

Company Type: Software Development Dates Employed: Mar 2017 – Present Employment Duration: 1 yr 6 mos Location: Monterrey, NL, Mexico

- Led a team of 5 Sr & Mid-level designers
- Helped to turn a new design busines unit from pilot to profitable in <12 months</li>
- Achieved operational optimum performance, reducing Design team's bench from around 50% to less than 10%
- Developed a structured hiring process for Full Stack Designers
- Implemented custom career paths and individual skill maps + career ladders
- Mastered facilitation + quick validation skills by running 20+ (Google Ventures) Design Sprints

### 2011-2016

# Co-founder & Director Raidho Aesthetics

Company Type: Digital Design Services
Dates Employed: Mar 2011 – Mar 2017
Employment Duration: 6 yrs 1 mo
Location: Monterrey, NL, Mexico

- Led a team of 10 (Designers + non-designers)
- Scaled a company from "garage mode" to a strong studio with national recognition
- Operationalized our individual approach to design, translated to templates, processes and practices
- Directed and/or supervised key areas of the company such as Strategy, Finance, Talent, Sales and Operations
- Directed and / or executed a multitude of challenging and exciting, multimedia design projects (editorial, web, video, animation, branding, etc.)

### **Education**

### 2007 - 2010

CEDIM© (Centro de Estudios Superiores de Diseño de Monterrey)

Degree Name: Lic. en Diseño Gráfico y Nuevos Medios (4.5 years program on Graphic Design & New Media)

Field Of Study: Graphic Design Dates attended: 2007 – 2010

### Language

Spanish — Native SpeakerEnglish — Business Level

## Interests

- All things Design, Tech & Entrepreneurship
- Human behaviour, psychology and philosophy
- Leadership & human development
- Community programs & events
- · Videogames, films & interactive media